Have you ever noticed when you ask someone to talk
你有没有注意到
about a change they're making for the better in their personal lives,
当你向别人问及 他们为改善自己的生活所做的改变时
they're often really energetic?
他们通常都是充满活力的？
Whether it's training for a marathon,
不管这个改变是为马拉松准备
picking up an old hobby,
还是重新拾起一份过去的爱好
or learning a new skill,
再或者是学习一门新技能
for most people,
对大多数来说
self-transformation projects occupy a very positive emotional space.
自我改变通常包含着一个积极的情感方向
Self-transformation is empowering,
自我改变是一个自我赋权的过程
energizing, even exhilarating.
充满活力或者让人非常愉悦兴奋
I mean just take a look at some of the titles of self-help books:
看看那些有关自我帮助的书籍的名字就知道了
"Awaken the Giant Within,"
“叫醒内在的巨大力量”
"Practicing the Power of Now,"
“掌控当下的力量”
or here's a great one we can all relate to,
或者这里有一个典型的
"You are a Badass:
“你不是个循规蹈矩的人”
How to Stop Doubting Your Greatness and Start Living an Awesome Life."
“如何停止怀疑你的卓越指出以及开始一份精彩的生活”
(Laughter)
（笑声）
When it comes to self-transformation,
当事情和自我转变有关系的时候
you can't help but get a sense of the excitement.
你所感受的兴奋感是无法控制的
But there's another type of transformation
但是，也有另外一种类型的转变
that occupies a very different emotional space.
这其中的情感倾向是非常不同的
The transformation of organizations.
关于集体的转变
If you're like most people,
就像和大多数的人反应一下
when you hear the words "Our organization is going to start a transformation,"
当你听到“我们的组织”将会有一些变化的时候
you're thinking, "Uh-oh."
你会想“不是吧”
(Laughter)
（笑声）
"Layoffs."
“要裁员啦”
The blood drains from your face,
连你脸上的血液都沸腾了
your mind goes into overdrive,
你的思维开始坐上了过山车
frantically searching for some place to run and hide.
此刻最想做的时候就是逃离或者找地方躲起来
Well, you can run,
当然，你可以跑掉
but you really can't hide.
但是，你根本无处可藏
Most of us spend the majority of our waking hours
我们中的大多数的大部分时间
involved in organizations.
都是在集体中度过的
And due to changes in globalization,
由于全球一体化带来的一些改变
changes due to advances in technology
和科技进步所带来的转变
and other factors,
以及其他的一些因素
the reality is our organizations are constantly having to adapt.
事实的真相是，我们的组织必须连续不断的去适应
In fact,
事实上
I call this the era of "always-on" transformation.
我把这个叫做“改变永不停止的时代”
When I shared this idea with my wife Nicola,
当我把这个想法和我太太Nicola分享的时候
she said, "Always-on transformation?
她问到“永不停止的改变”？
That sounds exhausting."
这听起来让人觉得很疲惫
And that may be exactly what you're thinking --
这就和你想的一样
and you would be right.
而且你可能是对的
Particularly if we continue to approach the transformation of organizations
特别是，当我们持续向着组织改变方向靠近的时候
the way we always have been.
也就是我们一直以来的样子
But because we can't hide,
但是，因为我们无法躲藏
we need to sort out two things.
我们需要弄清楚两件事情
First,
第一
why is transformation so exhausting?
为什么改变如此令人疲惫？
And second, how do we fix it?
第二，我们应该怎么解决？
First of all,
首先
let's acknowledge that change is hard.
我们必须要承认，改变是困难的
People naturally resist change,
人们自然而然的抗拒改变
especially when it's imposed on them.
特别是这种改变是强加在他们身上的时候
But there are things that organizations do that make change even harder
而且有一些组织把改变这件事情变得更难了更让人疲惫
and more exhausting for people than it needs to be.
尽管改变本身并没那么糟糕
First of all,
比如说
leaders often wait too long to act.
领导们常常不会及时行动
As a result,
后果是
everything is happening in crisis mode.
所有的事情都在大家的危机情绪中发生了
Which, of course, tends to be exhausting.
这种情绪当然会导致“精疲力尽”
Or, given the urgency,
或者对于紧急情况来说
what they'll do is they'll just focus on the short-term results,
他们会做的是基于短期内会有所结果的事情
but that doesn't give any hope for the future.
这对未来并不会有什么好的改观
Or they'll just take a superficial, one-off approach,
或者他们只会采取一些表面的，一次性的措施
hoping that they can return back to business as usual
希望他们可以如同往常一样开展以往的工作
as soon as the crisis is over.
当这种危机结束的时候
This kind of approach
这种方式
is kind of the way some students approach preparing for standardized tests.
就和学生为了标准考试准备的方式一样
In order to get test scores to go up,
只是为了得到理想的分数
teachers will end up teaching to the test.
老师们最终沦只为分数忙碌
Now, that approach can work;
目前阶段，这种方式是有效的
test results often do go up.
考试结果会变好
But it fails the fundamental goal of education:
但是却失去了让学生能够在未来成功的
to prepare students to succeed over the long term.
教育的本质职能
So given these obstacles,
所以，面对这些困难的时候
what can we do
我们能够做什么呢
to transform the way we transform organizations
应该要改变改造组织的方式
so rather than being exhausting,
而不是让人觉得精疲力尽
it's actually empowering and energizing?
改变本身是让人有权利掌控感和经济充沛的吗？
To do that, we need to focus on five strategic imperatives,
为了达到这样的目的，我们应该关注五个战略要点
all of which have one thing in common:
这所有的要点都有一个相同的前提
putting people first.
就是把人放在第一位
The first imperative for putting people first
第一个以人为本的要点
is to inspire through purpose.
是在目的中激励大家
Most transformations have financial and operational goals.
大多数的改革都是有财务和管理目的的
These are important and they can be energizing to leaders,
这些因素很重要，同时对领导来说是振奋人心的
but they tend not to be very motivating to most people in the organization.
但对于组织中的其他大多数人来说，却不那么振奋人心
To motivate more broadly,
为了更宽泛的激励大家
the transformation needs to connect with a deeper sense of purpose.
这样的转变需要更好的和目标感结合
Take LEGO.
拿乐高举个例子
The LEGO Group has become an extraordinary global company.
乐高集团在有力的领导下已经是一个及其大的国际化集团
Under their very capable leadership,
已经变成了非常大的国际化集团
they've actually undergone a series of transformations.
事实上，他们也经历过一系列的改革
While each of these has had a very specific focus,
他们所有的改革都有一个非常明确的目标
the North Star,
比如说，具有连接和指导功能的
linking and guiding all of them,
北星商场计划
has been Lego's powerful purpose:
以及成为了乐高强有力的目的
inspire and develop the builders of tomorrow.
那就是：启发和培养未来的主人翁们
Expanding globally?
或者是为了企业的国际化的扩张？
It's not about increasing sales,
这并不是为了增长销售额
but about giving millions of additional children access to LEGO building bricks.
只是为了让成千上万的孩子可以享受乐高的乐趣
Investment and innovation?
投资和动机？
It's not about developing new products,
这也不是为了开发新产品
but about enabling more children
这是为了促使孩子们
to experience the joy of learning through play.
在游戏中找到学习的乐趣
Not surprisingly,
这并不让人觉得惊讶
that deep sense of purpose tends to be highly motivating to LEGO's people.
这种心底的目的认同感极大的激励了乐高的所有员工
The second imperative for putting people first
以人为本的第二要点
is to go all in.
就是全力以赴
Too many transformations
对于大多数的改革来说
are nothing more than head-count cutting exercises;
只是一场裁员运动
layoffs under the guise of transformation.
用改革来掩饰裁员的目的
In the face of relentless competition,
在激烈的竞争面前
it may well be that you will have to take the painful decision
这可能是你需要作出的一个痛苦决定
to downsize the organization,
减少组织的规模
just as you may have to lose some weight in order to run a marathon.
就和你为了完成马拉松需要减轻一些体重一样
But losing weight alone
但是只是减轻体重
will not get you across the finish line with a winning time.
并不会让你成为马拉松的赢家
To win
为了成为冠军
you need to go all in.
你需要全力以赴
You need to go all in.
重要的事情，再说一遍，全力以赴
Rather than just cutting costs,
并不仅仅是减少成本
you need to think about initiatives
你需要去思考那些在中期
that will enable you to win in the medium term,
让你取胜的动机
initiatives to drive growth,
那些会促使增长的动机
actions that will fundamentally change the way the company operates,
那些可以从本质上改变公司运作的行动
and very importantly,
还有非常重要的一点
investments to develop the leadership and the talent.
‘加大投资去培养领导团队和那些有才华的人
The third imperative for putting people first
以人为本的第三要点
is to enable people with the capabilities
就是促使员工获得在改革过程中或者改革以后
that they need to succeed during the transformation and beyond.
使他们成功的技能
Over the years I've competed in a number of triathlons.
在这些年终，我所经历的铁人三项中
You know, frankly, I'm not that good,
老实说，我并不是非常擅长
but I do have one distinct capability;
但是我却是是有一项特别的能力
I am remarkably fast at finding my bike.
我能非常迅速的找到我的自行车
(Laughter)
（笑）
By the time I finish the swim,
当我完成游泳的时候
almost all the bikes are already gone.
几乎所有的自行车都不见了
(Laughter)
（笑）
Real triathletes know that each leg --
老资格铁人三项参赛者都知道所有的项目
the swim, the bike, the run --
游泳、自行车、长跑
really requires different capabilities,
所需要的技能其实是不一样的
different tools,
不同的工具
different skills, different techniques.
不同的技能以及不同的技巧
Likewise when we transform organizations,
这和我们改造组织是一样的
we need to be sure that we're giving our people
我们需要确定我们给我们的员工的技能和工具
the skills and the tools they need along the way.
是他们在过程中所需要的
Chronos,
a global software company,
一个全球的软件生产商
recognized the need to transfer from building products --
意识到他们需要把构建产品
software products --
软件产品
to building software as a service.
变成一种软件服务
To enable its people to take that transformation,
为了促使他们的员工接受这样的改变
first of all they invested in new tools
首先，他们对可以促使员工监控功能运用的
that would enable their employees to monitor the usage of the features
新工具进行了投资
as well as customer satisfaction with the new service.
同时也对客户对于新服务的满意度进行了关注
They also invested in skill development,
他们也对员工技能提高进行了培训投入
so that their employees would be able
所以他们的员工可以这个方面
to resolve customer service problems on the spot.
也良好的解决了客户服务中的问题
And very importantly,
还有非常重要的一点
they also reinforced the collaborative behaviors that would be required
他们同时也加强了需要给客户提供
to deliver an end-to-end seamless customer experience.
端到端无缝体验的的协作方式
Because of these investments,
正是因为这些投资
rather than feeling overwhelmed by the transformation,
而不是被改变本身搞得焦头烂额
Chronos employees actually felt energized
Chronos的员工在他们的新岗位上
and empowered in their new roles.
感到活力以及富有掌控感
In the era of "always-on" transformation,
在一个改变永不下线的时代
change is a constant.
变化是持续不断
My fourth imperative therefore
第四个首要关注点
is to instill a culture of continuous learning.
就是需要灌输一种长期学习的文化
When Satya Nadella became the CEO of Microsoft
当Satya Nadella在2014年
in February 2014,
当上微软的CEO的时候
he embarked on an ambitious transformation journey
为了让这个企业在一个移动和云时代具有竞争力
to prepare the company to compete in a mobile-first, cloud-first world.
他开启了一段富有野心的改变旅程
This included changes to strategy,
这包括战略上的改变
the organization
对于公司来说
and very importantly, the culture.
非常重要的，文化
Microsoft's culture at the time was one of silos and internal competition --
微软当时主要是简仓文化（一种企业架构文化）和内部竞争
not exactly conducive to learning.
这对于学习文化的构建并没有帮助
Nadella took this head-on.
Nadella采取了正面直上的方式
He rallied his leadership around his vision
为了形成有活力的学习文化
for a living, learning culture,
他根据自己的想法，整合了自己的领导方式
shifting from a fixed mindset,
从固定思维转变也就是说
where your role was to show up as the smartest person in the room,
你要做团体里面最聪明的人
to a growth mindset,
想要培养一个不断进步的心态
where your role was to listen, to learn and to bring out the best in people.
你需要倾听别人、学习和激发人们最好的一面
Well, early days,
早些日子
Microsoft employees already noticed this shift in the culture --
微软的员工们已经意识到文化中的这种转变
clear evidence of Microsoft putting people first.
也就是微软把人放在第一位
My fifth and final imperative is specifically for leaders.
我的第五个也就是最后一个首要观点是特别针对领导者的
In a transformation,
在转变的过程中
a leader needs to have a vision,
一个领导者需要有一个方向
a clear road map with milestones,
一个有明确目标的计划
and then you need to hold people accountable for results.
然后你需要让人们为结果负责
In other words, you need to be directive.
换而言之，就是你需要为他们指出方向
But in order to capture the hearts and minds of people,
为了洞察大家的心态和想法
you also need to be inclusive.
你还需要具有包容能力
Inclusive leadership is critical to putting people first.
包容性的领导方式就是严格的把人放在第一位
I live in the San Francisco Bay area.
我住在三番海湾区域
And right now,
现在
our basketball team is the best in the league.
我们的篮球队是联盟里面的第一名
We won the 2015 championship,
我们在2015年拿到了冠军
and we're favored to win again this year.
而且我们也很可能拿下今年的冠军
There are many explanations for this.
为此，他们做了很多准备
They have some fabulous players,
他们召集了一些很有实力的球员
but one of the key reasons
但是最关键的一原因之一
is their head coach, Steve Kerr, is an inclusive leader.
是因为他们的教练Steve Kerr 是个具有包容性的领导
When Kerr came to the Warriors in 2014,
当Kerr2014年来勇士执教的时候
the Warriors were looking for a major transformation.
勇士正在寻求改变
They hadn't won a national championship since 1975.
1975年之后他们就再也没有赢得过冠军
Kerr came in, and he had a clear vision,
Kerr来了之后，他有一个清晰的想法
and he immediately got to work.
并且，他立马投入了工作
From the outset,
从一开始
he reached out and engaged the players and the staff.
他就让工作人员和球员一起工作
He created an environment of open debate and solicited suggestions.
他创造了一个可以公开辩论和寻求建议的环境
During games he would often ask,
在比赛期间，他会问一些问题
"What are you seeing that I'm missing?"
比如，“你看到了什么是我错过的？”
One the best examples of this came in game four of the 2015 finals.
最好的一个例子是，2015决赛第四轮的时候
The Warriors were down two games to one
勇士二比一落后
when Kerr made the decision to change the starting lineup;
Kerr决定换掉初始阵容
a bold move by any measure.
不管从哪个角度来说，都是一个非常大胆的举动
The Warriors won the game and went on to win the championship.
勇士赢了那场比赛并且在之后拿了赛季冠军
And it is widely viewed
这个决定被广泛评价为
that that move was the pivotal move in their victory.
那场胜利中非常关键的转变
Interestingly, it wasn't actually Kerr's idea.
有意思的是，这并不是Kerr的主意
It was the idea of his 28-year-old assistant, Nick U'Ren.
是他28岁助理Nick U'Ren的主意
Because of Kerr's leadership style,
正是因为Kerr的领导风格
U'Ren felt comfortable bringing the idea forward.
让Nick U'Ren轻松的提出自己的想法
And Kerr not only listened,
Kerr不仅了解了他的想法
but he implemented the idea
还实施了这个想法
and then afterwards,
并且赛后
gave U'Ren all the credit --
还把所有的荣誉都给了助理U'Ren
actions all consistent with Kerr's highly inclusive approach to leadership.
这些都符合Kerr高度包容性的领导方式
In the era of "always-on" transformation,
在一个需要持续转变的时代
organizations are always going to be transforming.
组织需要不断的进行改变
But doing so does not have to be exhausting.
但是转变本身并不需要让人觉得筋疲力尽
We owe it to ourselves,
这是我们欠自己的
to our organizations
欠组织的
and to society more broadly
更大了来说，欠社会的
to boldly transform our approach to transformation.
为了勇敢的转变我们对待转变的方法
To do that,
为了达到这个目的
we need to start putting people first.
我们需要把人放在第一位
Thank you.
谢谢
(Applause)
（掌声）